<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scleronomous Rex</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Scleronomous Rex</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MDI: Weeks 1 - 3</title>
      <link>/2019/02/20/log-weeks-1-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/20/log-weeks-1-3/</guid>
      <description>Prelude Many of the R chunks below require these R packages (Kolde 2019, Dowle and Srinivasan (2019), Neuwirth (2014)):
library(pheatmap) library(data.table) library(RColorBrewer)  Reading The first step in the project is to understand the tool we are using. Therefore a study of Mason et al. (2016) and reading the manual of the associated program were the first steps. Expecting that this would have difficulties scaling to nine datasets different sampling methods were researched (Bardenet, Doucet, and Holmes 2017).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An introduction to MDI</title>
      <link>/2019/02/19/an-introduction-to-mdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/19/an-introduction-to-mdi/</guid>
      <description>Multiple Dataset Integration If we have observed paired datasets \(X_1=(x_{1,1},\ldots, x_{n,1})\), \(X_2=(x_{1,2},\ldots, x_{n,2})\), where observations in the \(i\)th row of each dataset represent information about the same individual. We would like to cluster using information common to both datasets. One could concatenate the datasets, adding additional covariates for each individual. However, if the two datasets have different clustering structures this would reduce the signal of both clusterings and probably have one dominate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My research interests include Bayesian clustering applied to &amp;lsquo;omics data to extract biological information. Within &amp;lsquo;omics we have huge quantities of data; interpreting this and creating a coherent story of disease is a non-tirivial problem. My aim is to use Bayesian clustering methods (particularly non-parametric methods) in the area of immunology to help contribute to the understanding of disease.
Previously I have worked with Paul Kirk, Laurent Gatto and Ollie Crook to extend Multiple Dataset Integration (MDI), an unsupervised clustering method based upon Dirichlet processes, to a semi-supervised predictive tool in spatial proetomics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>